<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>high-level synthesis on Rachit Nigam</title>
    <link>/tags/high-level-synthesis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in high-level synthesis on Rachit Nigam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;&amp;nbsp;Rachit Nigam 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 11:33:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/high-level-synthesis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA programming for the rest of us</title>
      <link>/post/predictable-accelerator-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 11:33:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/predictable-accelerator-design/</guid>
      <description>THIS IS A DRAFT POST. DO NOT DISTRIBUTE.
 This is quick overview of my research on Dahlia, a new programming language that leverages sub-structural types to make hardware design predictable.
 This blog post assumes some familiarity with reconfigurable architectures and High-Level Synthesis. If you want a quick overview on those, check out my blog post on compiling for the reconfigurable future.
High-Level Synthesis (HLS) is the idea of transforming functional descriptions of programs into performant and efficient hardware designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling for the Reconfigurable Future</title>
      <link>/post/reconf-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 11:59:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/reconf-future/</guid>
      <description>A TLDR on why you should care. FPGAs, a form of reconfigurable architectures, already power a large number of datacenter applications. With FPGA acceleration becoming mainstream, it is the perfect opportunity to think about programming models for designing next-generation high-performance hardware.
 Moore&amp;rsquo;s law is in its death throes. With Global Foundries announcing that they are no longer pursuing 7nm production nodes, fabrication companies focusing on incremental improvements, and the end of the arguably more important Dennard scaling, we&amp;rsquo;re entering a new era where general purpose architectures are no longer the solution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>