<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Posts on Rachit Nigam</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Posts on Rachit Nigam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;&amp;nbsp;Rachit Nigam 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling for the Reconfigurable Future</title>
      <link>/post/reconf-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 11:59:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/reconf-future/</guid>
      <description>A TLDR on why you should care. FPGAs, a form of reconfigurable architectures, already power a large number of datacenter applications. With FPGA acceleration becoming mainstream, it is the perfect opportunity to think about programming models for designing next-generation high-performance hardware.
 Moore&amp;rsquo;s law is in its death throes. With Global Foundries announcing that they are no longer pursuing 7nm production nodes, fabrication companies focusing on incremental improvements, and the end of the arguably more important Dennard scaling, we&amp;rsquo;re entering a new era where general purpose architectures are no longer the solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Two Years of My PhD</title>
      <link>/post/first-two-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:40:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-two-years/</guid>
      <description>With the end of the Spring ’20 semester a month away, I have spent almost two academic years at Cornell. A quick rundown of everything that happened:
Failures  Short paper on FuTIL rejected from LCTES ’20. Rejected from Facebook fellowship ’20. Dahlia rejected from ASPLOS ’20 with two weak rejects. Rejected from Microsoft research internship for summer ’19. Rejected from Qualcomm fellowship application ’19. Rejected from the Facebook fellowship ’19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cost of Virtualizing CS Conferences</title>
      <link>/post/virtual-cs-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 23:15:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/virtual-cs-conferences/</guid>
      <description>Conferences in computer science are an odd occurrence. Unlike most other research fields which primarily focus on publishing in journals, conferences ended up being the primary publication and presentation venue in CS. They also became the place where researchers network with each other, learn about ongoing research, and drink beer with their grad school buddies.
Because of this, conference presentations and networking play an incredibly important part of a junior researcher&amp;rsquo;s career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Management for PhD Students</title>
      <link>/post/project-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 22:10:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/project-management/</guid>
      <description>Collaborations in systems research is how I&amp;rsquo;ve built some of the best tools in my research. A larger teams means an expanded vision and being able to pursue more ambitious ideas but it also incurs an overhead &amp;ndash; team management. Effectively managing a team and keeping all team members up to date can be stressful and a daunting task. I think one way to approaching management tasks is by asking a few concrete questions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Fail</title>
      <link>/post/learn-to-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 07:20:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/learn-to-fail/</guid>
      <description>I often describe the basic philosophy of research using a metaphor: bash your head in a wall over and over till you find a way to break it and then repeat it ad nauseam. Sometimes you&amp;rsquo;ll know where the cracks in the wall are, and sometime you&amp;rsquo;ll know what angle you need to hit the wall with your head, but fundamentally, you&amp;rsquo;re hitting your head into a wall.
This is perhaps an unnecessarily graphic description of what research is like but the point I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get across is that research is hard and that failure is the expected outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD@Cornell: The Free Agent system</title>
      <link>/post/free-agent-cornell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 08:27:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/free-agent-cornell/</guid>
      <description>Deciding which graduate school you&amp;rsquo;re going to spend the next n years of your life is one of the hardest decision of your life. One of the things that made is hard for me was deciding between Cornell and my other top choice was Cornell&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Free agent system&amp;rdquo;. Here is a short post about what the system is and why it worked for me.
Graduate School Admissions For most schools in the US, when you apply to a PhD program, students are usually picked out by one or more professors who think you&amp;rsquo;d be a good fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t be Programming Languages researchers</title>
      <link>/post/pl-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 21:52:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/pl-research/</guid>
      <description>Instead of being a judgement of what PL research should be, this short post is simply a reflection of my research interests and what role PL plays into it.
 During a recent PLDG talk, the speaker said, &amp;ldquo;I think that, as a community, PL people have a moral responsibility to step in and say, ‘No, you&amp;rsquo;re having fun wrong!’&amp;rdquo; While I have no qualms about the comment itself (jokes can be useful tool in presentations), it led me to think about the way PL research is applied in new domains.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>